Guide to the Bill Dixon Papers MSS.481
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I. Music, 1936, 1941, 1959-2012; 125.72 Linear Feet in 30 record cartons, 39 flat boxes, 17 tall LP boxes, 24 manuscript boxes, 5 oversize flat boxes, 1 rolled storage box, and 2 flat-file folders.; 402.54 Gigabytes in 1,214 digital files.
  - Subseries I.B: Performance Recordings, 1960-2011; 75 Linear Feet in 30 record cartons, 25 flat boxes, 16 LP boxes, 1 manuscript box, and 1 cassette box
    - Art Davis, Undated; cuid37588 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_548)
    - Autumn Sequence from a Paris Mary (Feigin's Edition, Tape 1), Undated; cuid37589 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1622)
    - Bass and Trumpet, Undated; cuid37590
    - Ben Hall, Undated; cuid37591
    - Berlin Celebration Orchestra -- Bill Dixon Soloist, Undated; cuid37592 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2262)
    - Bill Dixon -- "Tea Dust" on Piano, Undated; cuid37593 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_588)
    - Bill Dixon "Badura-Skoda", Undated; cuid37594 (Box 12, 1 inch video reel 481_408)
    - Bill Dixon -- Bavaria Kopierwerk Videotransform, Undated; cuid37595 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2252)
    - Bill Dixon and Bill Cole, Undated; cuid37596 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1737)
    - Bill Dixon and Cecil Taylor (CD 1), Undated; cuid37597 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1713)
    - Bill Dixon and Cecil Taylor (CD 2), Undated; cuid37598 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1714)
    - Bill Dixon and Cecil Taylor Duet, Undated; cuid37599 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_465)
    - Bill Dixon and Cecil Taylor Duet Compilation, Undated; cuid37600 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1996)
    - Bill Dixon -- Live Performance, Undated; cuid37601
    - Bill Dixon and Cecil Taylor, Undated; cuid37602
    - Bill Dixon and David Bindman, Undated; cuid37603
    - Bill Dixon and J. L. Perform in Guelph, Ontario, Undated; cuid37604
    - Bill Dixon and Leslie Winston, Bennington College, Undated; cuid37605
    - Bill Dixon and Stephen Haynes Rehearse with Orchestra (5/21-5/22), Undated; cuid37606
    - Bill Dixon and the Exploding Star Orchestra, Undated; cuid37607
    - Bill Dixon and Tony Oxley, Undated; cuid37608
    - Bill Dixon Ensemble, Total Music Meeting, Jazz Festival Berlin, Undated; cuid37609
    - Bill Dixon in San Francisco, Undated; cuid37610
    - Bill Dixon Orchestra, Undated; cuid37611
    - Bill Dixon Orchestra SoCo Vision Festival, Undated; cuid37612
    - Bill Dixon Orchestra Work, "For Franz," New York City, Undated; cuid37613
    - Bill Dixon Performance, Undated; cuid37614
    - Bill Dixon Performances at Wesleyan University and Vision Festival, Undated; cuid37615
    - Bill Dixon, Stephen Horenstein, Hayden Carruth, Undated; cuid37616
    - Bill Dixon -- Wesleyan Sound, Creative Music Orchestra, Undated; cuid37617
    - Bill Dixon and Hong Ping, Undated; cuid37618
    - Bill Dixon and Jared van Dongen, Undated; cuid37619 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2454)
    - Bill Dixon and Stephen Horenstein Duet, Undated; cuid37620 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1469)
    - Bill Dixon and Tony Ackerman, Undated; cuid37621 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1029)
    - Bill Dixon and Tony Oxley -- "Sequenced x B", Undated; cuid37622 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2496)
    - Bill Dixon Concert #1: "Serendipity", Undated; cuid37623 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1329)
      Featuring Bill Dixon, Bob Ralston, Reggie Johnson, and Rashid Ali; the tape's original case was retained
    - Bill Dixon Ensemble, Undated; cuid37624 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1349)
    - Bill Dixon Ensemble Concert, Undated; cuid37625 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1576)
    - Bill Dixon Excerpts, Undated; cuid37626 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1582)
    - Bill Dixon Live: "Webern," "Velvet," "Windswept Winterset," "Llaattiinnoo", Undated; cuid37627 (Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1526)
    - Bill Dixon on Piano and Trumpet, Undated; cuid37628 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_071)
    - Bill Dixon on Piano, Paul Robeson House, Bennington College, Undated; cuid37629 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_065)
    - Bill Dixon Practicing Trumpet, Undated; cuid37630 (Box 60, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2149)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet Rehearsal, Undated; cuid37631 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1079)
    - Bill Dixon Solo at Wesleyan University, Undated; cuid37632 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2271)
    - Bill Dixon Solo Piano, Piece for Pat Lagg, Undated; cuid37633 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2055)
    - Bill Dixon Talk after Quartet Performance, Undated; cuid37634 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1653)
    - Bill Dixon Trumpet Solos, Undated; cuid37635 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1489)
    - Bill Dixon and David Bindman Duet, Undated; cuid37636 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_638)
    - Bill Dixon's Piano Songs, Undated; cuid37638 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_068)
    - Borah Bergman and Evan Parker, Undated; cuid36864 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_177)
    - Cello, Rehearsal Material, Undated; cuid37639 (Box 56, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1408)
    - Children's Puppet Music, Trumpet Solo, Undated; cuid37640 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1344)
    - Cecil Taylor String Quartet, Undated; cuid37641
    - Cecil Taylor Trio, Undated; cuid37642
    - Citizens Orchestra, Undated; cuid37643
    - Compilation of Performances in Donaueschingen, Hudson, New York, and London, Undated; cuid37644
    - Conscripts, Undated; cuid37645
    - Compilation Tape -- "Dusty Rose," Ensemble, Haynes Senior Piece, Undated; cuid37646 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2010)
    - Compilation Tape -- Bill Dixon Solos, Undated; cuid37647 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1987)
    - Compilation Tape -- Ensemble, Widoff, Bass Duets, Undated; cuid37648 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1957)
    - Compilation Tape -- Music Excerpts, Undated; cuid37649 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1967)
    - Compilation Tape -- Performances, Undated; cuid37650 (Box 67, Vhs 481_1148)
      Duration: 108 minutes
    - Compilation Tape -- Performances and Rehearsals, Undated; cuid37651 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1124)
      Duration: 100 minutes
    - Compilation Tape -- "Webern," "Shrike," Miscellaneous Excerpts, Undated; cuid37652 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2497)
    - Composition for Piano, Undated; cuid37653 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_092)
    - Compositions, Electric Piano, Undated; cuid37654 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_058)
    - Concert Master, Undated; cuid37655 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1706, 481_1705, 481_1707)
    - Concert, Undated; cuid37656 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_477)
    - Concert, First Edit, Undated; cuid37657 (Box 76, U-matic 481_2368)
    - "Contes, La Nappe Volante de Vent du Nord", Undated; cuid37658
    - Dances, Undated; cuid37659
    - Donaueschingen -- Solo Trumpet, Undated; cuid37660
    - Donaueschingen and Hudson, Undated; cuid37661
    - Donaueschingen Solo, Undated; cuid37662
    - Duets, Undated; cuid37663
    - David Weiss, Undated; cuid37664 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1296)
    - "Dew Horse" with Dance and Choreography by Judith Dunn, Undated; cuid37665 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1325)
    - "Dew Horse", Undated; cuid37666 (Box 77, Betamax 481_2356)
    - Bill Dixon on Bass, Guitar, Undated; cuid37667 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_482)
    - Bill Dixon -- Jennings Trumpet Practice, Undated; cuid37849 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_046, 481_051, 481_052, 481_055)
    - Dixon -- Free 8th Rainbow Reel, Undated; cuid37668 (Box 98, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2172)
      Reel 481_2172 in Box 98 was identified as moldy in September, 2022. This item is currently isolated from other items by housing it in a polyethylene bag with a desiccated board and RH monitor strip. If this strip indicates an RH greater than 50%, the Preservation department should be contacted ASAP. Do not open this packaging without contacting the Preservation Department.
    - Bill Dixon and Cecil Taylor Duets, Undated; cuid37669 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1595)
    - Bill Dixon and Bindman -- "Resequenced Composite", Undated; cuid37670 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1716)
    - Bill Dixon "Insert #1", Undated; cuid37671 (Box 76, U-matic 481_2364)
    - Bill Dixon Performance "LEC-DEM", Undated; cuid37672 (Box 98, Half inch video reel 481_2666)
      Format: Sony CV; Duration: 64 minutes; Preservation Note: High amount of buzz and hiss on tape. Video lighting is very dark.
    - Bill Dixon Performance "Probably for Film or Video", Undated; cuid37673 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1465)
    - Dowdell Concert with Bill Dixon on Tenor Saxophone, Undated; cuid37674 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_725)
    - Dramatic Reading with Music, Undated; cuid37675 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2507)
    - Duets: Bill Dixon and Henry Grimes at the Stone, Bill Dixon and Cecil Taylor, Undated; cuid36884 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2053)
    - Duets with Widoff, Undated; cuid37676 (Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1515)
    - Ellington Composition, Arranged for Large Ensemble and Voices by Bill Dixon, Undated; cuid37677 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1985)
    - Elliot Stevens and Ben Hall, Undated; cuid37678
    - Ensemble -- August, Undated; cuid37679 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1336, 481_1337)
    - Ensemble, Undated; cuid37680 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1283)
    - Ensemble Performance, Undated; cuid37681 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2530)
    - Ensemble Recording Master "For Franz Seiter", Undated; cuid37682 (Box 16, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1323)
      This tape was rehoused and original case with its annotations was retained.
    - Ensemble Rehearsal, Undated; cuid37683
      - Audio (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1473)
      - Papers (Box 213, Folder 19)
    - Eric Zinman -- Concert at NEC, Undated; cuid37684 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_489)
    - European Scan, Undated; cuid37685 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1065)
    - European Scan, Undated; cuid37686 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1066)
    - European Scan, Undated; cuid37687 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1080)
    - Bill Dixon with Ensemble and Singers, Undated; cuid37688 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_730)
    - "The Music You Hear Has Little To Do With The Content of this Film" by Leland Price -- Practice Session, Undated; cuid37689 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_985)
      Color positive with sound.
    - "Firense", Undated; cuid37690
    - "For Franz" Rehearsal Fragments, Undated; cuid37691 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1724)
    - "For Franz", Undated; cuid37692
      - Audio (Box 61, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2231)
      - Electronic Records
    - Fortunato's Wedding From the Cathedral, Undated; cuid37693 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_451)
    - Glynis Loman, Undated; cuid37694 (Box 63, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2334)
    - Gomberg, Franz Hautzinger, Solo Trumpet, Undated; cuid37695
    - Hayne's Concert: "Duet" and "Untitled", Undated; cuid37696 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1623)
    - Improvisation: Dixon, Worali, Calabro, Colick, Undated; cuid37697 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1350)
    - "Index", Undated; cuid37698 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2512)
      Duration: 58 minutes; Preservation note: Side 2 is blank
    - "Index", Undated; cuid37699 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1634)
    - "It Never Entered…", Undated; cuid37700 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1593)
    - Jack Moore Piece, Undated; cuid37701 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1130)
      Duration: 5 minutes
    - Jack Moore and Bill Dixon Rehearsal, Undated; cuid37702 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_707, Box 28, Audiocassette 481_746)
    - Jack Moore and Bill Dixon Duet, Undated; cuid37703 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_736)
    - Jacob Lipkin, Undated; cuid37704 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1113)
    - Jazz Composers' Guild Orchestra Rehearsal Empty Audiocassette Case, Undated; cuid37705 (Box 98)
    - "Imagine the Sound" Jazz Tape from Spain (TV), Undated; cuid37706 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1127)
    - Bill Dixon Performs Bass and Guitar, Jennings, Bennington College, Undated; cuid37707 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_740)
    - Jerusalem New Music Ensemble (Recent Excerpts), Undated; cuid37708 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1543)
    - Jerusalem Rehearsal, Undated; cuid37709 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2253)
    - Jon Voigt and Craig S. Basses, Undated; cuid37710 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1050)
    - Josh Kirsch Reel, Undated; cuid37711 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1115)
      Duration: 6 minutes
    - Jerusalem, Donaueschingin, Bill Dixon and Tony Widoff in Hudson, Undated; cuid37712
    - Keith Thompson, Undated; cuid37713
    - Koln Piece -- Finalized, Undated; cuid37714
    - Karen Radler "Sounds," Solo Trumpet, Undated; cuid37715 (Box 60, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2151)
    - L. Nowk Concert (Ellington, Parker, Coltrane), Undated; cuid37716 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1801)
    - "The Last Thing We Did", Undated; cuid37717
    - Lecrone, Undated; cuid37718 (Box 10, 1 inch video reel 481_405)
    - Leslie Winston, Undated; cuid37719 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1085)
    - Leslie: Piano, Undated; cuid37720 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_448)
    - "Letters: Round Up the Usual Suspects", Undated; cuid37721 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2014)
    - "Letters: Round Up the Usual Suspects" Performance, Undated; cuid37722
    - "Letters: Round Up the Usual Suspects" (Version B 1), Undated; cuid37723 (Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1514)
      Duration: 22 minutes; Preservation note: Side 2 is blank
    - Leonard D. Skrowaczewski, Undated; cuid37724
    - Leopanar Witlarge, Undated; cuid37725
    - L'Escamoteur, Maikotron Unit, Undated; cuid37726
    - Megan Shubert and Ben Hall, Undated; cuid37727
    - Modus Operandi -- Bill Dixon Trio, Undated; cuid37728
    - Male Voice with Audience, Undated; cuid37729 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1474)
    - Milford Graves and Bill Dixon Duet Performance, New York City, Undated; cuid37730 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1727)
    - Misc. Music -- Monk, MJQ, Miles, Tyner, Taylor, Undated; cuid37731 (Box 57, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1453)
    - Miscellaneous Music (Recorded), Undated; cuid37732 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_635)
    - "Metamorphosis", Undated; cuid37733
    - "Metamorphosis," "Voices," "Nightfall Pieces", Undated; cuid37734
    - Money Jungle, Ellington, Miles Davis, Undated; cuid37735 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_495)
    - Monte Tubb, Undated; cuid37736 (Box 49, Quarter inch audio reel 481_115)
    - Music for Maureen's Dance, Undated; cuid37737 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_586)
    - Music for Solo Trumpet (Limited Edition), Undated; cuid37738 (Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1516)
    - Music to Maureen's Dance, Undated; cuid37739 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_195)
    - David Warren, Undated; cuid37740 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_641)
    - Karen Borca, Marco Eneidi, Jackson Krall, W. M. Parker, Undated; cuid37741 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_179)
    - My Funny Valentine -- Bill Dixon / Janna Levenstein, Undated; cuid37742 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_455)
    - Nadi Qamar, Undated; cuid37743 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_561)
    - Nancy Goodfriend Soprano, Virginia Sircy Piano, Undated; cuid37744 (Box 49, Quarter inch audio reel 481_114)
    - New Texture Pantonal Fellowship, Undated; cuid37745
    - Nick B. [Illegible], Undated; cuid37746 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_559)
    - Nightclub Performance of "Dusty Rose" - Live, Undated; cuid37747 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_471)
    - Compilation Tape -- "November: 1981, "Penthesilea," "The Second Son," "The Sirens," "Another Quiet Feeling", Undated; cuid37748 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1601)
    - Compilation Tape -- "November: 1981," "Penthesilea," "The Sirens", Undated; cuid37749 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1600)
    - "October" Recordings, Undated
      - Video -- 1 of 11 (Box 74, Betacam sp 481_2115)
      - Video -- 2 of 11 (Box 74, Betacam sp 481_2116)
      - Video -- 3 of 11 (Box 74, Betacam sp 481_2117)
      - Video -- 4 of 11 (Box 74, Betacam sp 481_2118)
      - Video -- 5 of 11 (Box 74, Betacam sp 481_2119)
      - Video -- 6 of 11 (Box 74, Betacam sp 481_2120)
      - Video -- 7 of 11 (Box 74, Betacam sp 481_2121)
      - Video -- 8 of 11 (Box 74, Betacam sp 481_2122)
      - Video -- 9 of 11 (Box 74, Betacam sp 481_2123)
      - Video -- 10 of 11 (Box 74, Betacam sp 481_2124)
      - Video -- 11 of 11, cuid37750 (Box 77, Betacam sp 481_2125)
        Duration: 31 minutes
    - Orchestra Piece, Undated; cuid37761
    - Orchestra Piece III, Undated; cuid37762 (Box 57, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1455)
    - "Penthesilea" -- Rehearsals and Performances, Undated; cuid37763 (Box 45, Audiocassette 481_2601, 481_2602, 481_2604, Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2603, 481_2605, 481_2606, 481_2607, 481_2608, 481_2609, 481_2610)
    - Performance Compilation: Donaueschingen, Solo Flute, London, Undated; cuid37768
    - Performance in Finland, Undated; cuid37769 (Box 98, Audiocassette 481_1633)
      Audiocassette 481_1633 in Box 98 was identified as moldy in September, 2022. This item is currently isolated from other items by housing it in a polyethylene bag with a desiccated board and RH monitor strip. If this strip indicates an RH greater than 50%, the Preservation department should be contacted ASAP. Do not open this packaging without contacting the Preservation Department.
    - Piano, Undated; cuid37770 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_066, 481_078, Box 20, Audiocassette 481_097)
    - Piano, Bass, Tenor, Undated; cuid37773 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_181)
    - Piano Compositions, Undated; cuid37774 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_064)
    - Piano Compositions, Undated; cuid37775 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_088)
    - Piano Fragment, Undated; cuid37776 (Box 47, Audiocassette 481_2754)
    - Piano Sketches, Undated; cuid37777 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1027)
    - Piano Solos, Undated; cuid37778
      - Audio (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_063)
      - Electronic Records
    - Piano and Trumpet, Undated; cuid37780 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1471, 481_1477)
    - Piano Songs, Undated; cuid37781 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_060, 481_081, 481_085, 481_087, 481_091, Box 20, Audiocassette 481_095, 481_098)
    - Piano, Tenor Saxophone Exercises with Stephen Horenstein, Undated; cuid37788 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_710)
    - Piece for Karen Gerley, Undated; cuid37790 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_206)
    - Piece for Stan Payson, Piece for Mary Kinal, Undated; cuid37791 (Box 51, Quarter inch audio reel 481_161)
    - Piece for Wisconsin -- Orchestra, Undated; cuid37792 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_636)
    - Places -- Shelley Lubin, Undated; cuid37793 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_714)
    - Poetry and Music -- Sherley Anne Williams, Bertram Turetsky, Undated; cuid37794 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_656)
    - Program D #1-18, Undated; cuid37795 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2453)
    - Quartet Performance, St. Marks Danspace, Undated; cuid37796
    - Quebec Performance -- Bass Clarinet, Piano, Bass, Trumpet, Undated; cuid37797
    - "Quinacridone" Orchestra Work, Undated; cuid37798
    - Rehearsal of Composed Music, Possibly Arthur Brooks, Undated; cuid37799 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_493)
    - Rehearsal / City street scenes, Undated; cuid37800 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_1000)
      Black and white reversal print; Silent; Preservation note: Appears to change film orientations at cement splice closest to tails.
    - Rehearsal, Undated; cuid37801
    - Rehearsal, Undated; cuid38995 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1137)
    - Ron Stabinsky, Undated; cuid37802
    - Ron Stabinsky, Undated; cuid37803
    - Ron Stabinsky Piano Solos, Undated; cuid37804
    - Relay Trumpets and Piano, Undated; cuid37805 (Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1518)
    - "Relay," Berlin, Undated; cuid37806 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1630)
    - Riverside Church Piece, Performance 2, Bennington College, Undated; cuid37807 (Box 61, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2238)
    - Rome, Undated; cuid36883 (Box 45, Audiocassette 481_2558)
    - S. J. Zappa, Nick Skrowaczeski, Mark Leonard, Undated; cuid37808 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_655)
    - Shellin Lubin, Undated; cuid37809 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_744)
    - Alan Silva [illegible label], Undated; cuid37810 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_503)
    - Short Sample of Soprano Practice, Undated; cuid37811
    - Simon Lott II, Undated; cuid37812
    - Skrowaczewski Zappa Duo, Undated; cuid37813
    - Stefano Scodanibbio, Undated; cuid37814
    - Small Orchestra Piece, Undated; cuid37815 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_337)
    - Snaps Chromatique, Undated; cuid37816 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1114)
      No audio; transferred from 16mm film
      Duration: 23 minutes
    - Solo Saxophone, Undated; cuid37817 (Box 14, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1103)
      This tape was rehoused and the original container was retained.
    - Songs: Piano, 3 Versions, Undated; cuid37822 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_076)
    - Spectre, Undated; cuid37823 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1645)
    - Stanton Davis, Undated; cuid37824 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_555)
    - Steve Horenstein, Undated; cuid37825 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1073)
    - "Summerdance", Undated; cuid37826
    - Bill Dixon Talk and Performance, Undated; cuid37827 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_473)
    - "Tea Dust", Undated; cuid37828 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_590)
    - "There's Gold In Them Thar Hits" - Carl Landa, Pianist-Composer, Undated; cuid37829 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_501)
    - Tony Ackerman and Bill Dixon Duet, Undated; cuid37832 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1287)
    - Tony Oxley, Bill Dixon Donaueschingen, Cecil Taylor Solo, Undated; cuid37833
    - Trombone, Undated; cuid37834
    - Trumpet, Undated; cuid37835
    - Trumpet and Bass, Undated; cuid37836
    - Trumpet and Koto, Undated; cuid37837
    - Tracing Bill Dixon Trumpet Solo, Undated; cuid37839 (Box 60, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2155)
    - Trumpet, Undated; cuid37840 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_041)
    - Trumpet, Undated; cuid37841 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_042)
    - Trumpet, Undated; cuid37842 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_043)
    - Trumpet, Undated; cuid37843 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_044)
    - Trumpet, Undated; cuid37844 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_045)
    - Trumpet, Undated; cuid37845 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_047)
    - Trumpet, Undated; cuid37846 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_056)
    - Trumpet, Undated; cuid37847 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_080)
    - Trumpet, Koto, Undated; cuid37848 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1602)
    - Trumpet Solo, Shellen Cubin Voice and Guitar, Analysis of Material, Undated; cuid37850 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1493)
    - Trumpet Solos, Undated; cuid37838
      - Audio (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_048, 481_050, 481_053, 481_075, 481_082, Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1501, Box 56, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1405, Box 98, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1497)
      - Electronic Records
    - Trumpet Solos and Duet with Shakuhachi, Undated; cuid37855 (Box 60, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2150)
    - Trumpet, Mingus, George Russell Othello Ballet Suite, Undated; cuid37856 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1503)
    - Unknown [Illegible] Trumpet, Undated; cuid37857 (Box 56, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1427)
    - Vibes, Undated; cuid37858 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1490)
    - "Voices," "Fancy Foot," "Summerdance", Undated; cuid37859
    - "Voices," "Intents and Purposes", Undated; cuid37860
    - Wesleyan University Orchestra and New York City Vision Festival, Undated; cuid37861 (Box 70, Vhs 481_1128)
      Duration: 120 minutes
    - William II Talk - Good Piano, Trumpet, Undated; cuid37862 (Box 98, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1351)
    - "Winter Song, 1964" Rehearsal, Undated; cuid37863
    - Work on Material for Compositions: Bill Dixon and Steve Horenstein, Undated; cuid37864 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_739)
    - Work on Material for Voice and Piano, Undated; cuid37865 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_483)
      Vocal part has been transcribed from a trumpet solo.
    - "Work Paint," "Prologue + 10 Dances", Undated; cuid37866
      - Audio (Box 98, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1495)
      - Papers (Box 213, Folder 22)
    - "You Don't Know What Love Is", Undated; cuid37867 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_634)